# Sankar Mukherjee

Kolkata, India +91 8420369268 sanmuk21@gmail.com

https://sankamuk.github.io/

## Summary

I have been working on **<u>Data Engineering</u>** and Data Infrastructure Developer. I have experience both in On-Premise & Cloud environments.

In latest project was working with leading <u>Global Fiinance Data & Analytics</u> company to build their <u>next generation data platform (Adavance Data Workbench)</u>. This has been build using Databricks, Airflow, RDS (Postgres), etc over AWS Cloud. Have worked on migration of old legacy data applications (mostly for Energy data) into new platform while also build new ones (e.g. Cargo tracking). Work has been primarily focused around Data Pipeline & Backend Batch jobs creation.

### Skills

- Big Data
  - Hadoop (7 Yrs.), Spark (6+ Yrs.), Airflow (3+ Yr.), Databricks (1.5 Yr.)
- Java EE Application and HTTP Server
  - ☐ Websphere Application Server (6 Yrs.), JBoss (3 Yrs.), Apache HTTP Server (6 Yrs.)
- Development
  - Python (5+ Yrs.), Java (3 Yrs.), Reat JS
- Managed File Transfer
  - Axway CFT (3 Yrs.), Axway Secure Transport (1 Yr.)
- Build Engineering
  - ANT (2 Yrs.), Maven (3 Yrs.), **Jenkins** (3 Yrs.), **Git** (3 Yrs.)
- Automation and DevOps
  - ☐ **Shell Scripting** (10 Yrs.), **Ansible** (3 Yrs.), Rundeck (1 Yr.), GitOps (1 Yrs.)
- Containers
  - □ **Docker** (3 Yrs.), **Kubernetes** (2 Yrs.)
- Monitoring and Performance Engineering
  - Elastic Search(1 Yrs.), Prometheus (2 Yrs.), Grafana/Kibana (2 Yrs.), JMeter (1 Yr.)
- Operating Platform and Cloud
  - ☐ **Linux** (10 Yrs.), **Azure** (1.5 Yrs.), **AWS** (2 Yr.)

## Experience

JANUARY 2023 - TILL DATE

### Senior Specialist - Data Engg. / LTIMindtree

Working for Global Finanance Data & Analytics Company on building there next generation data platform on AWS using Databricks, Airflow, etc. Driving migration & building new data systems into new platform.

APRIL 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022

### Senior Staff Engineer - Data Engg. / Altimetrik

As part of Data Engineering Team working for **US Bank** to build and deliver their Bigdata DataLake.

OCTOBER 2020 - APRIL 2021

#### Technical Lead / Societe Generale Global Solution

As part of Data and Platform Engineering Team working for <u>French Bank</u> to build and deliver their Big data DataLake both on premise and on public cloud Azure.

OCTOBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2020

### **Hadoop Expert /** Gigaspaces Technologies

As Hadoop Expert in Platform Engineering Team working for <u>French Bank</u> to build and deliver there DataLake solution for marketing channel. Involved in designing and setting up environment and develop standards and sample solutions for applications to be hosted on the same.

JANUARY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

### **Technology Specialist / Accenture**

Global Technical Lead for Middleware and BigData Technologies for one of the **Global Pharma** client for Accenture IO.

August 2014 - November 2015

## **Senior Middleware Engg. /** Standard Chartered Banking Group

Part of Middleware Engineering group, worked on implementing tight standards and consistent, comprehensive processes for managing the entire Java EE App Server life cycle.

JULY 2013 - AUGUST 2014

### Technical Lead / Wipro Limited

Websphere Level 3 Service delivery resource for **UK banking** client. Build new application server environments and prepared them for run mode administration.

AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2013

### **Technical Services Profession / IBM**

Senior Middleware Engineer for <u>US Insurance</u> client. Also was part of Middleware Automation team for IBM, we delivered automation solutions used across all Middleware clients.

## Senior Engineer / TCS

Senior developer and module lead for Digital Asset Management Application for  ${\color{red} {\bf US~automobile}}$  client.

## **Education**

2008

## **Bachelor of Technology / University of Calcutta**

Major in Computer Science and Engineering.

### **Achievements**

Customer Champion for delivering first version of the Airflow based Dynamic Workflow
engine Altimetrik
Core Value Award for helping client in building there Next Generation DW with Hadoop –
Accenture
Celebrating Performance Award, for efforts in monitoring automation – <u>Accenture</u>
Certificate of Appreciation for excellence in delivery – <u>Lloyds Banking Group</u>
Appreciation for Authoring WAS Configuration Extractor Library. – <u>IBM</u>
Certificate of Acknowledgement for resolving long standing issue in EVenue Process. –
Chrysler Group LLC
Certificate of Acknowledgement for Outstanding effort to achieve highest level of customer
satisfaction. – <u>Chrysler Group LLC</u>
Certificate of Acknowledgement from TCS for Outstanding effort to achieve highest level of
customer satisfaction. – <u>TCS</u>
Awarded On-The-Spot award for efforts in successful BCP drill of TIN environment at NSDL
project. – <u>TCS</u>

## **Certifications**

Ц	Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark 3.0
	Java Standard Edition 6 Programmer Certified Professional
	IBM Certified WebSphere Application Server Network Deployment
	Oracle DBA 11g, SQL Fundamental

## Languages

- ☐ English (Fluent)
- ☐ Hindi (Good)
- ☐ Bengali (Fluent)